<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PISI SYSTEM "http://www.pardus.org.tr/projeler/pisi/pisi-spec.dtd">
<PISI>
    <Source>
        <Name>hedgewars</Name>
        <Homepage>http://www.hedgewars.org/</Homepage>
        <Packager>
            <Name>H. İbrahim Güngör</Name>
            <Email>ibrahim@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Packager>
        <License>GPLv2</License>
        <Icon>hedgewars</Icon>
        <IsA>app:gui</IsA>
        <Summary>Worms-like Strategy Game</Summary>
        <Description>Hedgewars is a turn based strategy game but the real buzz is from watching the devastation caused by those pesky hedgehogs with those fantastic weapons - sneaky little blighters with a bad attitude!.</Description>
        <Archive sha1sum="a59e71d5bd9477a399407264889df41fe9e61200" type="tarbz2">http://download.gna.org/hedgewars/hedgewars-src-0.9.16.tar.bz2</Archive>
        <BuildDependencies>
            <Dependency>qt-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>libsdl-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-mixer-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-image-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-net-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-ttf-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>lua-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>fpc</Dependency>
        </BuildDependencies>
        <Patches>
            <Patch>default_fullscreen.patch</Patch>
        </Patches>
    </Source>

    <Package>
        <Name>hedgewars</Name>
        <RuntimeDependencies>
            <Dependency>qt</Dependency>
            <Dependency>libsdl</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-mixer</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-image</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-net</Dependency>
            <Dependency>sdl-ttf</Dependency>
            <Dependency>lua</Dependency>
        </RuntimeDependencies>
        <Files>
            <Path fileType="executable">/usr/bin</Path>
            <Path fileType="localedata">/usr/share/hedgewars/Data/Locale</Path>
            <Path fileType="data">/usr/share/hedgewars</Path>
            <Path fileType="data">/usr/share/applications</Path>
            <Path fileType="data">/usr/share/pixmaps</Path>
            <Path fileType="man">/usr/share/man</Path>
            <Path fileType="doc">/usr/share/doc/hedgewars</Path>
        </Files>
        <AdditionalFiles>
            <AdditionalFile owner="root" permission="0644" target="/usr/share/applications/hedgewars.desktop">hedgewars.desktop</AdditionalFile>
        </AdditionalFiles>
    </Package>

    <History>
        <Update release="12">
            <Date>2011-09-20</Date>
            <Version>0.9.16</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump.</Comment>
            <Name>H. İbrahim Güngör</Name>
            <Email>ibrahim@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="11">
            <Date>2011-01-18</Date>
            <Version>0.9.15</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump.</Comment>
            <Name>H. İbrahim Güngör</Name>
            <Email>ibrahim@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="10">
            <Date>2010-04-17</Date>
            <Version>0.9.13</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump:
             * Many new hats, hats visible while using rope and blowtorch
             * New weapons: Exploding barrels, birdy weapon, poisoning effect, dud mines, 
             * Alt weapon preview on rope, parachute
             * UFO changed to homing bee
             * AI uses new weapons, aware of fire, can fight in artillery mode
             * New options in ammo editing - crate probability, delays
             * Option of semi-opaque hog name tags to avoid fail when land is hidden by name
             * New sounds: British voicepack, walk sound for hedgehogs, additional bounce sounds
             * Notification sound when people join your room
             * Hogs react to throwing grenades / dynamite and when near them
             * New visual effects: dust on fall impact, smoke, shotgun shells, blink team name on start of turn, hogs pulling weapons out, falling flakes kicked by explosion and more
             * View ammo menu when not your turn
             * Contextual help when using weapons menu
             * 3D effect for waves
             * Fade effect when starting/stopping game
             * New game modes - place hedgehog, king mode, randomise starts, allies share ammo, disable girders
             * Shift + direction to turn without moving
             * New font for CJK text and better CJK detection
             * Team flags
             * Graphic of crate contents when picking up weapon/utility
             * Splashes/droplets when things fall in the water
             * 45 degree bounce when throwing grenades
             * Information on game rules when starting game
             * Knockball map (scripted map)
             * Maze generator for new random maps
             * new crazy map template
             * New olympics, desert themes, visual updates to many other themes
             * Background texture for land for a 3d effect on explosions
             * Frontend able to delete teams
             * Ignore/friends lists in frontend
             * Updated options in frontend: independent toggles for frontend/game sound/music, select locale
             * Lua scripting for easy creation of missions and special maps.
             * Many bug fixes, speed optimizations, translation updates
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="9">
            <Date>2009-12-25</Date>
            <Version>0.9.12</Version>
            <Comment>
             * New weapons, maps, theme, visual effects, sounds, training modes
             * Dynamically zoom in/out in the battlefield with mouse wheel.
             * Updated graphics
             * Team chat
             * Remember net password
             * Implement room control delegation when host's connection fails
             * Colorize chat events in engine
             * Frontend improvements
             * Fix crash in replay caused by speech bubbles
             * Fix some desync causes
             * Fix rope bugs
             * Fix bugs in weapon selection code
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="8">
            <Date>2009-06-21</Date>
            <Version>0.9.11</Version>
            <Comment>Update doc path, remove strict deps for 2009.</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="7">
            <Date>2009-05-29</Date>
            <Version>0.9.11</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * Speech Bubbles - during your turn, have your hedgehog express himself.  In chat, use "regular speech"  'thought bubbles'  -action bubbles-  with the quote marks completely surrounding the entire typed text.  You can also use /hsa /hta /hya to fire off a bubble at the moment of your attack.
             * New graves and hats. Animated stars in the frontend and a new theme. Add missing graphics and maps.
             * Two new taunts - a /shrug and /juggle -ing.
             * New mobster voice! A remake of the default voice set. New theme music.
             * New game modes. Karma, any injury you caused (not including drowning) is dealt to you too, unless invulnerable.  Vampirism, where you feed off damage you deal, gaining 80% of it.  Artillery, where your hog can not move about.
             * Options to control mine quantity and timer.  Those are made use of in a Minefield scheme/weapon set as one of the default sets.
             * The sniper rifle demonstrated in previous news post.
             * Various fixes such as: prevent desync when a player quits, fix a crash at end of game in reduced quality, bug in synching changes to map and scheme in room, fix bug in disconnection from server, hedgehogs keep hats while jumping, bug in rope/parachute when drowning with active girder/teleport, bug in rope that on rare occasion deleted it on firing.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="6">
            <Date>2009-04-16</Date>
            <Version>0.9.10</Version>
            <Comment>Updated Turkish translation.</Comment>
            <Name>Uğur Çetin</Name>
            <Email>jnmbk@users.sourceforge.net</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="5">
            <Date>2009-04-16</Date>
            <Version>0.9.10</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * Many many more terrain generation options, maps can be huge, very small, caverns, caves, stepping stones, etc.
             * To accompany these new terrain generation options there are new themes and musical tracks
             * On top of this there are a ton of brand new preset maps, have your hogs fight on city scapes and lazy old men in hammocks!
             * Lots of new hats (total of 79 now!) and to add to the hats, some new voice work
             * A new type of weapon called a utility has been added, these weapons drop in utiltiy crates and boost your hedgehogs abilities, low gravity, laser sight, extra time, extra damage, forcefield
             * Alongside weaponsets we now have "scheme sets", this means you can save gameplay options into a scheme for later use. We've also added a whole load more options for you to use in your schemes, you can add borders to any map, disable mines, enable low gravity, make all hogs invincible, and more.
             * The server has been given a major upgrade, you can now reserve your name with your hedgewars.org account. At the moment there are no stats in game, but we may already begin tracking them to display them later, so remember to log in! We are also integrating the game with the website.
             * A new Despeckling gameplay feature removes stray pixels from the terrain after fires/big explosions
             * Graphics updates, language updates, music and sound updates across the board
             * Demos can now be played without the frontend
             * Weapons and hogs can now bounce off of the water if they hit it at the right speed/angle.. this can be used in a very interesting way with the rope ;)
             * Hedgewars can now generate your team for you if you're feeling lazy, it also generates random teams for "quick play" mode, and even uses appropriate hats. I.e. it will generate a ninja team, with ninja names/hats!
             * Changed girder functionality completely to make it a much more interesting and fun weapon!
             * Many more fixes and feature.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="4">
            <Date>2009-01-20</Date>
            <Version>0.9.9</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * Voicepacks, customize your teams voice!
             * Nice new visual statistics page after the match
             * Precise aiming, hold shift to aim more accurately
             * Improved lobby chat
             * Remote Control Plane weapon
             * A couple of additions to customization content (i.e. grave / fort / hat content)
             * Additional sound effects
             * Various tweaks and bug fixes
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="3">
            <Date>2009-01-08</Date>
            <Version>0.9.8</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * Better menu icon
             * Massive number of network play bugfixes
             * Now spectating works for those who joined after game start
             * New Drill rocket weapon
             * New Napalm strike weapon
             * New Super awesome super weapon
             * Land can now be set to be indestructable
             * Six brand new maps using new themes
             * Lots of new forts
             * Hellish hand grenade reworked
             * Brand new lobby and lobby chat
             * Spread of Melon Bomb fragments improved
             * Blowtorch bug fixes and improvements
             * Fixed a crash bug that occured when the engine had no room to place all Hedgehogs
             * More delay after jump, less delay after small fall for hedgehog
             * Limit max chat message length to 300 characters
             * Ammo menu no longer closes when user clicks on not yet available weapon
             * Ammo scheme bug fixes
             * Fire effect improved
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="2">
            <Date>2008-11-11</Date>
            <Version>0.9.7</Version>
            <Comment>Start fullscreen by default.</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="1">
            <Date>2008-11-10</Date>
            <Version>0.9.7</Version>
            <Comment>First release.</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
    </History>
</PISI>
