<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PSPEC SYSTEM "http://www.pardus.org.tr/projeler/pisi/pisi-spec.dtd">
<PISI>
    <Source>
        <Name>sylpheed</Name>
        <Homepage>http://sylpheed.sraoss.jp/en/</Homepage>
        <Packager>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Packager>
        <License>GPLv2</License>
        <Icon>sylpheed-128x128</Icon>
        <IsA>app:gui</IsA>
        <Summary>A lightweight email client and newsreader</Summary>
        <Description>Sylpheed is a simple and lightweight but featureful and easy-to-use e-mail client.</Description>
        <Archive sha1sum="618c6c5d385b654f685456b715064784263f6124" type="tarbz2">http://sylpheed.sraoss.jp/sylpheed/v3.1beta/sylpheed-3.1.0beta6.tar.bz2</Archive>
        <BuildDependencies>
            <Dependency>shared-mime-info</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gtk2-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gpgme-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>openldap-client</Dependency>
            <Dependency>compface-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gtkspell-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>enchant-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>pango-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>cairo-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>atk-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>fontconfig-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>libgpg-error-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>freetype-devel</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gdk-pixbuf-devel</Dependency>
        </BuildDependencies>
        <Patches>
            <Patch level="1">panel-transparency-fix.patch</Patch>
        </Patches>
    </Source>

    <Package>
        <Name>sylpheed-docs</Name>
        <IsA>data:doc</IsA>
        <Summary>Documentation files for sylpheed</Summary>
        <RuntimeDependencies>
            <Dependency release="current">sylpheed</Dependency>
        </RuntimeDependencies>
        <Files>
            <Path fileType="doc">/usr/share/doc/sylpheed/html</Path>
        </Files>
    </Package>

    <Package>
        <Name>sylpheed</Name>
        <RuntimeDependencies>
            <Dependency>shared-mime-info</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gtk2</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gpgme</Dependency>
            <Dependency>openldap-client</Dependency>
            <Dependency>compface</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gtkspell</Dependency>
            <Dependency>enchant</Dependency>
            <Dependency>pango</Dependency>
            <Dependency>cairo</Dependency>
            <Dependency>atk</Dependency>
            <Dependency>fontconfig</Dependency>
            <Dependency>freetype</Dependency>
            <Dependency>gdk-pixbuf</Dependency>
        </RuntimeDependencies>
        <Files>
            <Path fileType="executable">/usr/bin</Path>
            <Path fileType="doc">/usr/share/doc/sylpheed</Path>
            <Path fileType="localedata">/usr/share/locale</Path>
            <Path fileType="library">/usr/lib</Path>
            <Path fileType="data">/usr/share/pixmaps</Path>
            <Path fileType="data">/usr/share/applications</Path>
        </Files>
    </Package>

    <Package>
        <Name>sylpheed-devel</Name>
        <IsA>library</IsA>
        <Summary>Development files for sylpheed</Summary>
        <Files>
            <Path fileType="header">/usr/include/sylpheed</Path>
        </Files>
    </Package>

    <History>
        <Update release="47">
            <Date>2010-12-24</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta6</Version>
            <Comment>
                Version bump;
                - A new option 'Set only mail address when entering recipient from address book' was added.
                - The menu items 'Add to recipient/Cc/Bcc' were added to the address book.
                - On junk mail filtering, appropriate Junk folder for accounts will be selected.
                - When going offline, all current network sessions will be disconnected.
                - Low priority will be used for long timeout interval.
                - The behavior on opening folders and mark-read timing was modified again.
                - The HTML parser was fixed to handle 'a' tag correctly.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="46">
            <Date>2010-12-08</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta4</Version>
            <Comment>
                Version bump;
                - Leave messages on POP3 server for 7 days by default.
                - Clear temporary password if authentication fails.
                - Added an option 'Always mark as read when a message is opened'. This will bring back the previous behavior.
                - Added SOCKS4/5 proxy support.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="45">
            <Date>2010-09-02</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta3</Version>
            <Comment>Enable Attachment Tool Plug-in</Comment>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="44">
            <Date>2010-09-02</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta3</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to third beta for testing:
                * Drag and drop of addresses on the address book is supported now.
                * New plug-in 'Attachment Tool Plug-in' was added. It enables the removal of attachments in messages.
                * Virtual folders can be moved now.
                * 'Junk' special folder was added. It will be automatically created if not exist.
                * A new option 'Change current account on folder open' was added, and it is enabled by default.
                * On 'File - Save as...' dialog, '.eml' extension was added for the default file name.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="43">
            <Date>2010-08-17</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta2</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to second beta for testing:
              * On POP3 receiving, new messages are displayed on the summary view immediately. Folder switching is not required anymore.
              * The feature to combine partial messages (RFC 2046, message/partial) was added.
              * Users can move up/collapse/expand the folder view using left/right arrow key now.
              * When inline image setting is off, images are not displayed in the Attachment tab too.
              * The menu items 'Mark/Mark' and 'Mark/Unmark' were changed to 'Mark/Set flag' and 'Mark/Unset flag' for understandability.
              * The upper limit of auto-check interval was changed to 1000 minutes.
              * The source files of the English FAQ and manual were added.
              * The hidden &lt;account-id&gt; filter condition works now.
              * The crash when POP3 session was cancelled while processing received mail was fixed.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Fethican Coşkuner</Name>
            <Email>fethicanc@gmail.com</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="42">
            <Date>2010-06-15</Date>
            <Version>3.1.0_beta1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
              * Full automatic address completion was implemented. Users can also configure to use the previous behavior (start completion on Tab key).
              * The debug log output for filtering was added.
              * New plug-in APIs for update check and folder view were added.
              * A new option '--instance-id ID' was added. This allows users to run multiple instances of Sylpheed.
              * 'Open' menu was added to the attach context menu of the message composition window. This allows users to open attached files before sending.
              * English Sylpheed FAQ was updated.
              * Plug-ins are also loaded from user plug-in directory now.
              * The crash when using %f on IMAP messages at the action tool was fixed.
              * The crash when clicking tray icon menu 'Get from current account' when no account exist was fixed.
              * The bug that MIME flags were not set to imported mbox file and filtered sent messages was fixed.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="41">
            <Date>2010-04-17</Date>
            <Version>3.0.2</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to stable:
              * The random scrolling problem on selecting folders was fixed
              * The problem that config files are not updated after creating new accounts was fixed.
              * The problem that folder config file was not updated after changing IMAP or News account name was fixed.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="40">
            <Date>2010-03-17</Date>
            <Version>3.0.1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to stable: Several typos in dialogs were fixed. Use xdg-open to open browser (thanks to H. Ibrahim Gungor).</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="39">
            <Date>2010-02-24</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to stable:
             * Translation updates.
             * The bug that caused freeze when sending or receiving messages with STARTTLS and 'SSL certificate verify failed' dialog popped up.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="38">
            <Date>2010-02-19</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_rc</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new RC for testing:
             * 'Enable address auto-completion' setting was added
             * Some minor bugs were fixed
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="37">
            <Date>2010-02-12</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta8</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * The new filter match type 'is in addressbook' was added. This can be used from filtering, query search and quick search.
             * The new account setup dialog was implemented. It also supports easy Gmail setup.
             * The address completion was modified.
             * The spell-checking and PGP settings are preserved for draft messages now.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="36">
            <Date>2010-01-29</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta7</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * The feature to add new recipients to address book automatically on sending was added.
             * Color labels are saved on IMAP server now (partially compatible with Thunderbird).
             * The auto-wrapping setting is preserved for draft messages now.
             * The problem that beep sound was out when opening folders which were sorted in descending order was fixed.
             * The new plug-in APIs for compose window were added.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="35">
            <Date>2010-01-14</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta6</Version>
            <Comment>New beta: The bug where IMAP caches get wrongly deleted was fixed.</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="34">
            <Date>2010-01-13</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta5</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * The feature to customize the color label text was added.
             * The option to set only mail address of recipients when replying was added.
             * When messages are added to IMAP folders, received-date information is also set using Date header (mainly for Gmail).
             * Spellchecking re-enabled / a workaround for crash caused by enchant with zemberek was added.
             * The bug that caused freeze when remote IPC commands were executed.
             * The bug that IMAP caches with UIDs larger than INT_MAX were never deleted was fixed.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="33">
            <Date>2009-12-17</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta4</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * The folder icons renewed.
             * The setup dialog on the first run is user-friendly.
             * 'Last 7 days' added to the quick search options.
             * The number of matched messages is displayed at the side of quick search now.
             * Description is displayed on the quick search entry when it does not have focus.
             * Always show warning dialog when SSL certificate is expired.
             * The menu item to request disposition notification added to the compose window.
             * The button order of folder selection dialog was modified.
             * Disable update check by default (Pardus has its own package-manager for that).
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="32">
            <Date>2009-11-27</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta3</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * SHA1/MD5 fingerprint and validity period of certificate is now displayed when verification of server SSL certificate failed.
             * Address book is now sortable by each column.
             * Address book search feature was added.
             * The visibility of message number columns in the folder view is now configurable for each column.
             * The error check of socket connection became more strict.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="31">
            <Date>2009-11-16</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta2</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing:
             * Multi-threading fix: Sync failure when operating IMAP folders while IMAP communication
             * Multi-threading fix: IMAP folder search didn't work
             * Multi-threading fix: Freeze when update check dialog was popped up
             * Multi-threading fix: Crash on connection timeout
             * The unintended drag start on IMAP folders was fixed.
             * A dialog will be displayed while creating folder tree after creating IMAP accounts.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="30">
            <Date>2009-10-30</Date>
            <Version>3.0.0_beta1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to beta for testing:
             * Multi-threading support, reduces the situations where user actions are blocked.
             * Summary caches are updated on the fly (on receive/move/copy/delete), improves the performance of opening folders with many new messages.
             * Progress is displayed while scanning folders.
             * The user interface of address book was rewritten using the new API (GtkTreeView), reducing glitches.
             * Included Sylpheed English FAQ was updated.
             * Some bugfixes are made.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="29">
            <Date>2009-08-13</Date>
            <Version>2.7.1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * The feature to import and export .eml files was added.
             * Progress is displayed during import and export now.
             * The warning about non-exist plug-in directory was removed.
             * The comments within Content-Type header are handled now.
             * The order of signals emitted at moving messages was modified.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="28">
            <Date>2009-07-21</Date>
            <Version>2.7.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump :
             * The plug-in system was implemented (still experimental).
             * LibSylph (internal version) is built as shared library now.
             * The update check feature was implemented.
             * fsync() will be called after writing configuration files.
             * 'Send queued messages' is shown instead of 'Mark all read' in the context menu of the Queue folder.
             * The default command line options of spam filters were modified.
             * A crash bug on CSV import of the address book was fixed.
             * Several other bugfixes were made.
             * Move faq/manual files to documentation directory
             * Temporarily disable gtkspell, crashes the program
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="27">
            <Date>2009-05-04</Date>
            <Version>2.6.0</Version>
            <Comment>Update doc path, remove strict deps for 2009.</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="26">
            <Date>2008-12-19</Date>
            <Version>2.6.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new stable :
             * A workaround for raw-JIS filename used for attachments was made.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="25">
            <Date>2008-12-01</Date>
            <Version>2.6.0_rc</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new RC for testing :
             * The backups for configuration files are kept for four generations now.
             * Only new messages are counted when incorporating from local mbox.
             * In the folder selection dialog, only folders which are expanded in the folder view are expanded now.
             * The folders which should not be selected in the folder selection dialog became unselectable now.
             * The bug that the addressbook window was not refreshed when sender of message was added to the addressbook was fixed.
             * Several bugfixes were made.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="24">
            <Date>2008-11-17</Date>
            <Version>2.6.0_beta2</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing :
              * The menu was added to the remote POP3 mailbox window.
              * The sorting of remote POP3 mailbox was fixed.
              * The remote POP3 mailbox button was added to the toolbar.
            </Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="23">
            <Date>2008-09-29</Date>
            <Version>2.6.0_beta1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump to new beta for testing</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="22">
            <Date>2008-06-17</Date>
            <Version>2.5.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump, fix panel transparency, add spelling support</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="21">
            <Date>2008-04-14</Date>
            <Version>2.4.8</Version>
            <Comment>Use shared compface</Comment>
            <Name>Onur Küçük</Name>
            <Email>onur@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="20">
            <Date>2007-12-23</Date>
            <Version>2.4.8</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="19">
            <Date>2007-10-04</Date>
            <Version>2.4.7</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="18">
            <Date>2007-09-19</Date>
            <Version>2.4.6</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="17">
            <Date>2007-08-31</Date>
            <Version>2.4.5</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="16" type="security">
            <Date>2007-08-24</Date>
            <Version>2.4.4</Version>
            <Comment>Fix http://secunia.com/secunia_research/2007-70/advisory/</Comment>
            <Name>İsmail Dönmez</Name>
            <Email>ismail@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="15">
            <Date>2007-07-20</Date>
            <Version>2.4.4</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="14">
            <Date>2007-06-29</Date>
            <Version>2.4.3</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Doruk Fişek</Name>
            <Email>dfisek@fisek.com.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="13">
            <Date>2007-05-21</Date>
            <Version>2.4.2</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="12">
            <Date>2007-05-07</Date>
            <Version>2.4.1</Version>
            <Comment>Stable update and mark last update as security for CVE-2007-1558</Comment>
            <Name>İsmail Dönmez</Name>
            <Email>ismail@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="11" type="security">
            <Date>2007-04-20</Date>
            <Version>2.4.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="10">
            <Date>2007-01-16</Date>
            <Version>2.3.1</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="9">
            <Date>2006-12-23</Date>
            <Version>2.3.0</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="8">
            <Date>2006-11-17</Date>
            <Version>2.2.10</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="7">
            <Date>2006-10-07</Date>
            <Version>2.2.9</Version>
            <Comment>Add compface support</Comment>
            <Name>Onur Küçük</Name>
            <Email>onur@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="6">
            <Date>2006-09-23</Date>
            <Version>2.2.9</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="5">
            <Date>2006-08-02</Date>
            <Version>2.2.7</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="4">
            <Date>2006-06-27</Date>
            <Version>2.2.6</Version>
            <Comment>No more crashes in tr_TR in the menu -> view</Comment>
            <Name>Onur Küçük</Name>
            <Email>onur@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="3">
            <Date>2006-06-14</Date>
            <Version>2.2.6</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="2">
            <Date>2006-05-31</Date>
            <Version>2.2.5</Version>
            <Comment>Version bump</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
        <Update release="1">
            <Date>2006-04-12</Date>
            <Version>2.2.4</Version>
            <Comment>First release.</Comment>
            <Name>Ali Erdinç Köroğlu</Name>
            <Email>erdinc@pardus.org.tr</Email>
        </Update>
    </History>
</PISI>
